let set24 =
    [
        {
            question: `#1. Angiospermae is a division of kingdom Plantae. The main characteristic feature of angiosperms is: `,
            options:
                [
                    'A. Seeds are naked in fruits ',
                    'B. Seeds are covered with coats and are in fruits ',
                    'C. Fruits are without seeds ',
                    'D. Seeds are naked without fruits ',

                ],
            answer: `Answer: B`,
            exp: `Explanation: Angiosperms are the largest group of plants on Earth. There are approximately 270,000 known species alive today. There's probably one nearby right now. Angiosperms include all plants that have flowers and account for approximately 80% of all known living plants. Example of an angiosperm: Carpel of Broomrape plant Characteristics: Angiosperms are able to grow in a variety of habitats. They can grow as trees, shrubs, bushes, herbs, and small flowering plants. Some of the characteristics of angiosperms include: 1. All angiosperms have flowers at some stage in their life. The flowers serve as the reproductive organs for the plant, providing them a means of exchanging genetic information. 2. Angiosperms have small pollen grains that spread genetic information from flower to flower. These grains are much smaller than the gametophytes, or reproductive cells, used by non-flowering plants. This small size allows the process of fertilization to occur quicker in the flowers of angiosperms and makes them more efficient at reproducing. 3. All angiosperms have stamens. Stamens are the reproductive structures found in flowers that produce the pollen grains that carry the male genetic information. 4. Angiosperms have much smaller female reproductive parts than non-flowering plants, allowing them to produce seeds more quickly. 5. Angiosperms have carpels that enclose developing seeds that may turn into a fruit. 6. A great advantage for angiosperms is the production of endosperm. Endosperm is a material that forms after fertilization and serves as a highly nutritional food source for the developing seed and seedling. `
        },
        {
            question: `#2. Which of the following have an open circulatory system?  \n (i) Arthropoda  \n (ii) Mollusca  \n (iii) Annelida \n (iv) Cnidaria `,
            options:
                [
                    'A. (i) and (ii) ',
                    'B. (i) and (iii) ',
                    'C. (ii) and (iv) ',
                    'D. (ii) and (iii) ',

                ],
            answer: `Answer: A`,
            exp: `Explanation: The open circulatory system is common to molluscs and arthropods. Open circulatory systems pump blood into a cavity (hemocoel) with the blood diffusing back to the circulatory system between cells. Blood is pumped by a heart into the body cavities, where blood surrounds the organs. This system lacks a true heart or capillaries. The blood found in these organisms is a mix of blood and an interstitial fluid called as hemolymph. `
        },
        {
            question: `#3. Which adaptation of the frog differentiates it from the fish? `,
            options:
                [
                    'A. Ability to live in water also ',
                    'B. Lays eggs in water ',
                    'C. Have a streamlined body ',
                    'D. Presence of mucous glands in the skin ',

                ],
            answer: `Answer: A`,
            exp: `Explanation: Due to mucous glands, these enable the frog to leave the water and live an amphibious life on both land and in water. Fish do not need mucous glands as they don’t leave the water so don’t need to protect their skin from drying out. A frog cannot live solely in the water, they need to breathe air and would drown if they stayed in the water, fish need to stay in the water to survive.`
        },
        {
            question: `#4. Among the following choose the correct option that best describes the characteristics of spirogyra. `,
            options:
                [
                    'A. Multicellular, auto trophic, root like rhizoids. ',
                    'B. Cytoplasmic strands, autotrophic, presence of rhizome. ',
                    'C. Presence of male cones, nonvascular, filaments. ',
                    'D. Filamentous, presence of Cytoplasmic strands, presence of pyrenoids. ',

                ],
            answer: `Answer: D`,
            exp: `Explanation: The important characteristics of spirogyra are: 1. It is an unbranched, filamentous green algae occurring in the stagnant water so known as pond scum. 2. A mucilaginous covering or sheath is present which makes the surface slimy hence known as pond silk. 3. A double layered cell wall is present in which the outer wall is made of pectin and inner wall of cellulose. 4. A spirally coiled or ribbon shaped chloroplast with number of pyrenoids is present. 5. Reproduction occurs both in vegetative and sexual methods. 6. Vegetative reproduction is by fragmentation. 7. Sexual reproduction takes place by conjugation. 8. Three types of conjugation is found in spirogyra. They are i. scalariformconjugation, ii. Lateral conjugation, iii. Self conjugation. 9. The lifecycle of the spirogyra is haplobiontic.`
        },
        {
            question: `#5. Choose the option that best describes the characteristics of the kingdom to which the mushroom belongs:`,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) Unicellular prokaryotic organisms',
                    '(b) Saprophytic, eukaryotic, multicellular organisms ',
                    '(c) Unicellular eukaryotic organisms ',
                    '(d) Autotrophic eukaryotic organisms ',

                ],
            answer: `Answer: B `,
            exp: `Explanation: Answer B`
        },
        {
            question: `#6. Which of the following can sometimes be ‘zero’ for a moving body? \n i. Average velocity \n ii. Distance travelle \niii. Average speed \n iv. Displacement `,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) Only (i) ',
                    '(b) (i) and (ii) ',
                    '(c) (i) and (iv) ',
                    '(d) Only (iv) ',

                ],
            answer: `Answer: C`,
            exp: `Explanation: 1. The average velocity of an object is its total displacement divided by the total time taken. In other words, it is the rate at which an object changes its position from one place to another. Average velocity is a Vector quantity. The SI unit is meters per second. 2. The distance travelled is the path taken by a body to get from an initial point to an end point in a given period of time, at a certain velocity. If the velocity is constant: Distance = time * velocity. 3. The average speed of an object is the total distance traveled by the object divided by the elapsed time to cover that distance. It's a scalar quantity which means it is defined only by magnitude. A related concept, average velocity, is a vector quantity. A vector quantity is defined by magnitude and direction. 4. If an object moves relative to a reference frame—for example, if a professor moves to the right relative to a whiteboard, or a passenger moves toward the rear of an airplane—then the object’s position changes. This change in position is known as displacement. The word displacement implies that an object has moved, or has been displaced. Displacement is defined to be the change in position of an object. `
        },
        {
            question: `#7. Which of the following statement is correct regarding velocity and speed of a moving body? `,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) Velocity of a moving body is always higher than its speed ',
                    '(b) Speed of a moving body is always higher than its velocity ',
                    '(c) Speed of a moving body is its velocity in a given direction ',
                    '(d) Velocity of a moving body is its speed in a given direction ',

                ],
            answer: `Answer: D`,
            exp: `Explanation: Answer D`
        },
        {
            question: `#8. In a free fall the velocity of a stone is increasing equally ion equal intervals of time under the  effect oravitational force of the earth. Then what can you say about the motion of this stone? Whether the stone is having: `,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) Uniform acceleration ',
                    '(b) Non-uniform acceleration ',
                    '(c) Retardation ',
                    '(d) Constant speed ',

                ],
            answer: `Answer: A`,
            exp: `Explanation: Uniform or constant acceleration is a type of motion in which the velocity of an object changes by an equal amount in every equal time period. A frequently cited example of uniform acceleration is that of an object in free fall in a uniform gravitational field. The acceleration of a falling body in the absence of resistances to motion is dependent only on the gravitational field strength g (also called acceleration due to gravity). `
        },
        {
            question: `#9. If the displacement of an object is proportional to square of time, then the object moves with: `,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) Uniform velocity ',
                    '(b) Uniform acceleration ',
                    '(c) Increasing acceleration ',
                    '(d) Decreasing acceleration ',

                ],
            answer: `Answer: B`,
            exp: `Explanation: If the displacement of an object is proportional to the square of the time taken then the body is moving with uniformly accelerated motion as it will follow Newton's second equation of motion for a particular initial velocity, which can be given by,s=ut+\frac { 1 }{ 2 } a{ t }^{ 2 }s=ut+21at2.`
        },
        {
            question: `#10. In which of the following cases of motions, the distance moved and the magnitude of the displacement are equal? \ni. If the car is moving on a straight road \nii. If the car is moving in circular path \niii. The pendulum is moving to and fro iv. The earth is moving around the sun `,
            options:
                [
                    '(a) only (ii) ',
                    '(b) (i) and (iii) ',
                    '(c) (ii) and (iv) ',
                    '(d) only (i) ',

                ],
            answer: `Answer: D`,
            exp: `Explanation: If the car is moving on a straight road than the displacement is always equal to the distance, when an object is moving in the a straight path (displacement is defined as the shortest distance covered by a body)`
        }
    ]